<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stories on Nerd Coach</title>
    <link>https://nerdcoach.io/story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stories on Nerd Coach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nerdcoach.io/story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear is a muscle that you can release</title>
      <link>https://nerdcoach.io/story/fear-is-a-muscle-that-you-can-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nerdcoach.io/story/fear-is-a-muscle-that-you-can-release/</guid>
      <description>We used to have a book on the shelf called, “Love is Letting Go of Fear.”
I liked seeing the spine of it from across the room. That simple phrase sounded so wonderful and true. I may have even read the book once and understood it conceptually, but it did not actually help me let go of any fear.
I really had no idea what to do within myself to let go of fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Bets of Agile</title>
      <link>https://nerdcoach.io/story/the-hidden-bets-of-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nerdcoach.io/story/the-hidden-bets-of-agile/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Tischbeinahe, CC-BY-SA   Agile stories don’t tell us what to code; they are only examples. They offer small slices of the bigger abstractions that we’ll usually need.
Stories are tiny windows that we can peer through as we code. The simplicity of a story motivates and concentrates our creative effort. Their value is in boiling down the larger picture of the problem domain and what the customer really wants, in plain language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Technical Debt</title>
      <link>https://nerdcoach.io/story/managing-technical-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nerdcoach.io/story/managing-technical-debt/</guid>
      <description>Illustration by Siobhán K Cronin   Many linear feet of books have been written about the complexity of software development, estimation, cost control, QA, and so on.
Complexity is complex.
I want to share with you a handful of tried-and-true practices that have really helped me as an engineering manager when keeping technical debt under control in a growing project.
Keep points of flexibility in the right places Design your software as you would design a building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death By A Thousand Great Ideas</title>
      <link>https://nerdcoach.io/story/death-by-a-thousand-great-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nerdcoach.io/story/death-by-a-thousand-great-ideas/</guid>
      <description>No shortage of these.    found·er¹ (noun)
a person who establishes an institution or settlement.
the excited founders of a Silicon Valley startup
 At first, my co-founder Rahmin and I felt like we could do anything. We hadn’t set out with an idea — it was just, “Let’s start a company!” We’d found each other through a shared interest in continuing education, but we were interested in taking six months without committing to a specific path.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>